Mike Jacobi

Seattle, Washington, United States

mikerjacobi@gmail.com

425-445-1322

linkedin.com/in/mikerjacobi

https://mike.jagobi.com

Summary

Machine Learning Engineer with over ten years of backend engineering and leadership experience, seeking to support the needs of business and product teams using strong communication and entrepreneurial skills, and deploy mission-critical models and APIs

Experience



Machine Learning Engineer

Charmed

Aug 2023 - Present (5 months)

- Developed text-to-3D Gen Al system using PyTorch/Cuda, deployed via Docker on SageMaker
- Enhanced model accuracy by visualizing training artifacts, refining loss calculations, and optimizing hyperparameters
- Developed a sophisticated 3D object search platform with Elasticsearch and spaCy, achieving high precision metrics
- Implemented support APIs around model inference using AWS SAM, Lambda, S3, and DynamoDB

Senior Engineering Manager

Linden Lab

May 2022 - Aug 2023 (1 year 4 months)

- Oversaw a Backend Team of eight engineers, directing project planning, prioritization, recruitment, and fostering both career and technical development through regular one-on-one meetings
- Led the architecture and integration of JPMorgan Wallet, coordinating cross-organizational technical discussions
- · Owned Production operations, formulated incident response guidelines, communicated with internal and external stakeholders, ensured delivery and execution of postmortems for continuous improvement
- · Collaborated with Product, Finance, Legal, and Compliance teams, translating business requirements into technical designs
- Engaged in B2B customer interactions, participating in sales calls and guiding post-contract implementation processes
- · Served as the Engineering team's representative to Leadership, providing executive one-on-ones and weekly status reports



Principal Software Engineer

Linden Lab

Jun 2013 - May 2022 (9 years)

- Architected and executed business-core FinTech system, processing millions of credit card transactions and tens of millions of virtual transactions annually
- Upgraded the backend system to support multi-tenancy using OAuth2 role-based access control, increasing both security and scalability

- Developed essential microservices for user accounts, financial transactions, and compliance needs using Golang, Python, MySQL, and Redis
- Created a fuzzy PII matching system employing Elasticsearch for OFAC screening and duplicate account checking
- Implemented a flexible, generic throttle middleware using Go and Redis
- Operated and monitored Production using Datadog, and responded to incidents via PagerDuty

Postmasters Student

Los Alamos National Laboratory

2010 - 2013 (3 years)

Implemented a "smart" filesystem search using FUSE and MongoDB

Education

The University of New Mexico

MS, Computer Science 2011 - 2012

University of Montana

BS, Computer Science 2007 - 2011

Skills

Python • Go (Programming Language) • MySQL • PyTorch • docker • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • AWS Lambda • AWS SageMaker • TypeScript

Honors & Awards

Blastro - Personal Project

2023

- Blastro is a top down, 2D space shooter built in Godot
- Using the HuggingFace Diffusers library and Stable Diffusion to generate all game assets
- Training enemy movement behavior using reinforcement learning (RL) techniques

Sockhop - Personal Project

2022

- Sockhop is a browser-based video chat app (React, Node / Typescript) where participants can move themselves around a 2D space and play games together
- Try it here: sockhop.me/room/mountains